

Senior Solution Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Change Management, Coding, Testing, Software Development Life Cycle, Production Support, Resource Deployment, Java, SpringBoot, PostgreSQL



Current Designation: Senior Solution Engineer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Pegasystems Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree:

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Solution Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Change Management, Coding, Testing, Software Development Life Cycle, Production Support, Resource

Deployment, Java, SpringBoot, PostgreSQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Currently working as Senior Solution Engineer with Pegasystems, Hyderabad with 6 years of experience in the areas of Software Development (Requirement Gathering, Coding, Design, Support, Deployment)

Rich experience in software principles, design patterns and all phases of SDLC encompassing requirement analysis, coding, change requirements, technical design, implementation, deployment & production support

Contributed towards completion of multiple projects; actively participated in the Innovation Station Project and successfully worked on Automation Anywhere

Followed Agile Methodologies to deliver high-quality code in minimum time and budget with 100% quality & accuracy

Work Experience

Pegasystems as Senior Solution Engineer

Sep 2018 to Till Date

Technology Used: Java, Oracle 11g, Cassandra (NoSQL Database), PostgreSQL, Kafka, Rest API, Karate for API Testing Key Result Areas:

Managing software development activities which includes requirement gathering, coding, design, testing, development and deployment / implementation

Working on marketing B2b application and managing end-to-end development of various B2b use cases Coordinating with BAs for Requirement Gathering, Client & Testing Team to identify & improve the application performance

Integrating application with various third-party APIs; resolving integration & interface issues within various applications/systems

Documenting and maintaining low / high level designs documents for new features

Understanding process requirements and providing use cases for business, functional & technical requirements

Appearing in code review meetings with the teams and to discuss about the progress of projects

Customizing development plan, code, & design to ensure client satisfaction & delivery of project on time within the SLAs Resolving integration & interface issues within various applications or systems with key focus on optimizing application performance and scalability

Conducting system study and coordinating with team members for product documentation, system design & integration, coding, application maintenance

Attending stand-up calls with the clients & providing estimations & number of story points for user stories during sprint in Agile methodologies

Reviewing the issues in production region of application systems; preserving the back-up for production support activities

Synchrony Financial as Software Developer

Jul 2017 to Sep 2018

Technology used: Java, SpringBoot, HTML 5, JavaScript, Oracle 11g, RabbitMQ, Rest API, Pcf cloud foundry Highlights:

Worked with Agile Team on fraud call centre application, deployed application on PCF from on premise Engaged in automation of various functionalities used by call centre agents

Actively participated in the Innovation Station Project and successfully worked on Automation Anywhere Acted as a POC and developed bot for internal HR Team which can be integrated with Cisco Jabber

Intellect Design Arena as Software Developer

Jun 2014 to Jun 2017

Technology used: Java, Struts 1,HTML, JavaScript, Oracle 11g,Tomcat and WebLogic(for deployment) Highlights:

Successfully managed Retail and Corporate LOS Application for HDFC, Citibank, GE Capital, MF and Axis Bank Managed back-end and java technology development, including analysis, design and coding

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Malviya National Institute of Technology NIT Jaipur in 2014

PG: in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last	Used Experience	
WINDOWS, LINUX			
C, Java, Assembly (8085/86)			
MySQL			
HTML, CSS, JAVA SCRIPT			
Spring			
spring boot	0	1 Year(s) 0 N	lonth(s)
MicroServices	0	1 Year(s) 0 N	lonth(s)
Data Structures	0	4 Year(s) 0 N	lonth(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=d85eb9a25c7afa79d36315d52e25e90e0e0809024a415d130517155b0f...

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time